silverstripe.org 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy » SilverStripe

SilverStripe is committed to protecting your privacy. When you give us Personal Information, we only use it for the purpose for which it was collected, and we treat it according to the Privacy Policy laid out below.

Latest update: 21 August 2019

Contact email: [privacy@silverstripe.com](mailto:privacy@silverstripe.com?subject=Email%20privacy%40silverstripe.com "Email privacy@silverstripe.com")

## Scope of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers SilverStripe's treatment of information that we collect on our websites. It only applies to websites which SilverStripe owns and manages, specifically:

  * SilverStripe company website at [silverstripe.com](https://www.silverstripe.com/ "SilverStripe company website")
  * SilverStripe open source website [silverstripe.org](https://www.silverstripe.org/ "SilverStripe open source website")
  * SilverStripe CMS developer documentation at [docs.silverstripe.org](https://docs.silverstripe.org/ "SilverStripe CMS developer documentation")
  * SilverStripe CMS user documentation at [userhelp.silverstripe.org](https://userhelp.silverstripe.org/ "SilverStripe CMS user documentation")
  * SilverStripe CMS API documentation at [api.silverstripe.org](https://api.silverstripe.org/ "SilverStripe CMS API documentation")
  * SilverStripe CMS add-ons at [addons.silverstripe.org](https://addons.silverstripe.org/ "SilverStripe CMS add-ons")
  * SilverStripe community forum at [forum.silverstripe.org](https://forum.silverstripe.org/ "SilverStripe community forum")

## Personal Information

“Personal Information” refers to any information that can be used to identify you as an individual, and may include, but is not limited to: your name, email address, phone number, occupation, and other information required to provide a service, deliver a product, share marketing content, or carry out a transaction that you have requested.

We will always indicate before we collect any Personal Information from you and will only use it for the purposes specified at the time of collection. We will not change the way your Personal Information is used without your consent.

## What information do we collect?

### Activity history

SilverStripe uses server logs to register website visitor activity and downloads. Logged information may include timestamps, your client IP address (as it appears to the server), and the pages you visit. Logged information is not personally identifiable. However, if you identify yourself by filling out a form on one of our websites and providing us with Personal Information, any existing and future information collected about your activity history will be linked to your Personal Information.

Our server logs will not be shared with any third-party. However, from time to time, we may elect to publish aggregate statistics on visitor activity based on log information. We will never publish any personally identifiable information. 

Any use of activity history that we collect is subject to the provisions of this Privacy Policy.  

### Personal Information and contact details

At certain times, we will request Personal Information from you in connection with online registration or enquiry forms, when requesting product or service information, when downloading marketing content, or when providing comments or feedback on the site. We only collect Personal Information requested at the time of collection.

If you identify yourself by filling out a form on one of our websites and providing us with Personal Information, any existing and future information collected about your activity history will be linked to your Personal Information. Providing this information is voluntary. However, failure to provide Personal Information when requested may result in certain services or resources being unavailable to you. 

Any use of Personal Information and contact details that we collect is subject to the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

### Cookies and other tracking technologies

SilverStripe and its third-party service providers utilise cookies and tracking scripts on our websites. This is in order to administer the site, analyse trends, track users' movements around the site, and gather aggregated information about site visitors as a whole, such as which countries our website traffic originates from.

We may receive reports from these third-party service providers based on the use of their technologies on our websites on an individual as well as aggregated basis. For more information about the use of these technologies by our third-party service providers and how they use cookies, please refer to the following disclosures:

You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. For more information, we recommend that you view documentation on managing cookies for your specific browser. For example, [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647 "Managing cookies in Chrome"), [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences "Managing cookies in Firefox"), or [Edge](https://support.microsoft.com/en-nz/help/4468242/microsoft-edge-browsing-data-and-privacy-microsoft-privacy "Managing "). Note that if you reject cookies, normal website functionality will be unaffected, but your ability to access some features or areas of the website may be restricted.

## What do we do with the information we collect?

If you provide SilverStripe with your contact details for the purpose of online registration, submitting an enquiry, requesting product or service information, or downloading marketing content, we may use this information to get in contact with you. The purpose of that contact will be to respond directly to your enquiry or request, and in some cases, to determine if you have other needs we can respond to.

If you have downloaded marketing content from a SilverStripe website, we may contact you to determine if you have other needs that we can respond to. However, if you select a country within the European Union on the download form, you will be given the option to opt-out of receiving communications that you have not specifically requested.

If you submit a live chat through a SilverStripe website, your identity will remain anonymous until you provide personally identifiable information in the chat window. Once personally identifiable information has been provided, the conversation and your identity can be linked to our customer relationship management system.

When you subscribe to our newsletter, your email address is required in order to add you to the mailing list. You may unsubscribe from future mailings at any time either by contacting us or clicking unsubscribe in the email. Clicking unsubscribe will take you to your SilverStripe email preference centre where you can update any subscriptions you have to SilverStripe mailing lists.

Registering on the silverstripe.org website or community forum requires you to enter your email and create a password. You may also submit optional, additional Personal Information for your profile, including a profile picture, and select which information is published. This optional information can later be edited or deleted from your profile user settings.

When you submit a comment on our blog, you are required to enter your email address. The comment will be published but your email will not. You may additionally provide your name and website URL to link back to your website, both of which will be published.

### Information sharing

With the exception of any Personal Information you choose to publish on silverstripe.org or the community forum, or if you are a SilverStripe customer, information that we are required to share with a third-party in order to provide a service to you, no Personal Information collected on SilverStripe websites will be shared outside the company, other than with the third-party service providers named in this policy.

### Information security and retention

We make reasonable efforts to maintain a level of security that is appropriate to the risk associated with the processing of Personal Information. We maintain organisational, technical, and administrative measures designed to protect Personal Information held by SilverStripe against unauthorised access, destruction, loss, alteration, or misuse. Your Personal Information is only accessible to a limited number of SilverStripe employees who require access to that information to perform their duties. 

No information transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your Personal Information held by SilverStripe is not secure, please contact us immediately.

If you are a SilverStripe user or customer, we may retain your Personal Information as long as we are providing services to you. We may also retain Personal Information after our providing services to you has ceased, to the extent required to maintain compliance with our tax, accounting, and financial reporting obligations. Where we retain Personal Information, we do so in accordance with any limitation periods and record retention obligations imposed by applicable law. 

### EU residents

If you complete a form on a SilverStripe site and select a country of residence within the European Union, you will be given the option to opt-out of receiving future updates and marketing content from SilverStripe. You will also have the option to subscribe to newsletters from SilverStripe. You may unsubscribe from future mailings at any time either by contacting us or clicking unsubscribe in the email. 

## Where do we store information?

SilverStripe websites are hosted on Amazon Web Services with instances based in Australia, the United States, and Ireland. Additionally, our third-party service providers hold Personal Information belonging to SilverStripe customers, Partners, and users who have personally identified themselves through SilverStripe websites. For more information about our third-party service providers and their storage of information, please refer to the following disclosures:

## Links to third-party websites and user-contributed content

While this Privacy Policy applies to SilverStripe's websites only, those sites do contain links to third-party websites which we do not own or control. SilverStripe takes no responsibility for the privacy policies of these third-party websites.

SilverStripe moderates user contributions to its websites such as blog comments and forum posts. However, SilverStripe takes no responsibility for user-contributed content and may choose to disagree with the views expressed in those contributions. Views expressed in user-contributed content are the contributors alone.

## Accessing, updating, and correcting your information

SilverStripe will provide you with any Personal Information we hold about you upon request. To request this information, please contact us. In order to ensure that your Personal Information is accurate and up-to-date, please notify us of any changes to your Personal Information. If you have a user profile on a SilverStripe website that you wish to delete, you can request its deletion by contacting us.

## Questions or comments

If you have any privacy-related questions or comments related to this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@silverstripe.com?subject=Email%20privacy%40silverstripe.com).
